Emile Berliner Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 4. Books, 1879-1928, 3.5 linear feet
  - American Bell Telephone Co., v. the Overland Telephone Company of New Jersey, 1884 (Box-folder 10/1)
  - American Bell Telephone Co., v. the People’s Telephone Company et al, 1884 (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Dept. of Interior, United States v. American Bell Telephone, 1887; United States v. American Bell Telephone, 1885, 1887-1888 (Box-folder 10/3)
  - United States v. American Bell Telephone Co., oral argument for Mr. Storrow for the Bell Company on its demurrer, June, 1887, and oral argument of Mr. Dickerson for the Bell Company, 1888 (Box-folder 10/4)
  - The Telephone Appeals, oral argument of Mr. Dickerson, January 24 to February 8, 1887 (Box-folder 10/5)
  - The Telephone Appeals, oral argument of Mr. Storrow on the Drawbaugh defence, January 24 to February 8, 1887 (Box-folder 10/6)
  - History of the telephone, James Storrow before the Supreme Court, 1886 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - American Bell Telephone Co. v. Sylvanus D. Cushman et al, 1893 (Box-folder 10/8)
  - American Bell Telephone Co. v. National Telephone Manufacturing Co., v. Century Telephone Co. et al,, argument of Frederic H. Betts, 1899 (Box-folder 11/1)
  - American Bell Telephone Co. v. National Telephone Manufacturing Co. v. Century Telephone Co. et al,, brief for complainant, 1899 (Box-folder 11/2)
  - American Bell Telephone Co. v. National Telephone Co. Manufacturing Co. et al, argument at the hearing in support of the defense, by R.S. Taylor, 1899 (Box-folder 11/3)
  - American Bell Telephone Co. v. National Telephone Co. Manufacturing Co. et al, brief for defendants, 1895 (Box-folder 11/4)
  - American Bell Telephone Co. v. National Telephone Co. Manufacturing Co. et al, brief for complainant upon appeal, 1902 (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Gramophone Litigation, [1905?] (Box-folder 11/6)
  - The Electrician, Weekly Journal, v. 4, November 22, 1879, to May 15, 1880 (Box 29)
  - Telegraphic Journal and Electrical Review, v. 8, January–December, 1880 (Box 30)
- Series 5. Catalogs, 1895-1896, 6 folders
  Series 5 consists of catalogs from 1895 and 1896. Included is an advance list of new records from May 1895, a supplementary list of records from June 1985, a handwritten list of band music and recitations from July 1895, and a supplemental list of new gramophone records from June 1896.
  - Berliner Gramophone Co. complete catalogue (Box-folder 12/1)
  - List of plates, January, 1895 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - E. Berliner’s gramophone, 1895 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Advance list of new records, 1895 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Supplementary list of records, 1895 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Supplement list of new gramophone records, 1896 (Box-folder 12/2)
- Series 6. Correspondence, 1871-1926, 1946-1955, .5 linear feet
  This series includes some personal correspondence from Emile Berliner to Jacob Berliner, but the majority of correspondence pertains to business letters and copies of letters between Berliner and J.W. Hyatt, William P. Richards (D.C. Surveyor’s Office), Alfred C. Clark, James Rush Marshall, and others. This series is arranged in chronological order.
  - 1870-1871 (Box-folder 12/3)
  - 1881-1887 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - 1888-1889 (Box-folder 12/5)
  - 1890-1896 (Box-folder 12/6)
  - 1905-May, 1922 (Box-folder 12/7)
  - July 1922-1928 (Box-folder 12/8)
  - October 1926-November 6, 1926, undated (Box-folder 12/9)
  - November 7, 1926-November 24, 1926, undated (Box-folder 12/10)
  - 1946, 1955, undated (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Louise Berliner Frank King’s family tree research (Box-folder 12/12)
- Series 7. Journals and Diaries, 1889-1907, .5 linear feet
  Series 7 includes copies of Cora Berliner’s journal of her family’s trip to Germany in 1889 and Joseph Sander’s diaries from 1906 and 1907.
  - Journal of Cora A. Berliner, 1889-1890 (Box-folder 13/1)
    Includes copies.
  - Joseph Sanders’s diary, 1906 (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Joseph Sanders’s diary, 1907 (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Unidentified diary, undated (Box-folder 13/4)
- Series 8. Miscellaneous Materials, 1897-1929, .5 linear feet
  This series contains a variety of materials, including a 1927 report on the activities of the Association for the Prevention of Tuberculosis of the District of Columbia; copies of sheet music for the “Columbian Anthem,” which was written by Berliner; invitations; award certificates; and programs.
  - Report, Association for the Prevention of Tuberculosis of the District of Columbia, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Sheet music, invitations, award certificates, programs, 1896-1930 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Promotional materials for the Celotex Company, 1925 (Box-folder 13/6)
- Series 9. Notes and Papers, 1977-1928, .5 linear feet
  Series 9 contains notes made by Emile Berliner on many of the inventions and experiments he was working on during his lifetime. These include the electric telescope, organophone, batteries, broken-point microphone, a siphoning gas jet, and producing a tremolo (tremolo on a violin). The series also contains copies of a tribute to Berliner on his birthday from the board of directors of the Association for the Prevention of Tuberculosis, essays, speeches, and legal documents. Researchers will find a handwritten statement by Berliner describing his preferred funeral arrangements.
  - Notes on experiments, including electric telescope, broken-point microphone, gas jet, battery, and violin, 1877-1884 (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Experiment log and notes on experiments, including batteries, candle, light through electrolyte and magnetic field, and final development of the Blake transmitter, 1884-1923 (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Birthday tribute to Emile Berliner on his 75th birthday, publicity for Berliner’s acoustic cement cells, and Berliner’s funeral preferences, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Agreement between Joseph and Jacob Berliner, the Bell-Berliner system since 1879, a poem in German, an essay on the magnetic receiver, and a eulogy for Berliner (Box-folder 13/10)
  - “Wonders,” an essay describing the wonders found in everyday occurrences of scientific principles, 1897 (Box-folder 13/11)
  - Legal documents and notes in German, 1887-1891 (Box-folder 13/12)
- Series 10. Pamphlets, 1890-1929, 1951, undated, .5 linear feet
  This series contains copies of pamphlets describing the operating directions for the motor gramophone, the history of the gramophone, promotional pamphlets for the gramophone and acoustical tile, reports on installing acoustic tile at Drexel Institute, the microphone, and promotion of the Berliner biography by Frederic William Wile.
  - Gramophone (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Acoustics (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Microphone (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Telephone almanac, 1951 (Box-folder 14/4)
- Series 11. Patents, 1879-1909, .5 linear feet
  Copies of patents in this series include improvements in electrical contact telephones, designs for carpeting, improvements to telephone transmitters, gramophone improvements, floor coverings, apparatus for producing sound records, and Joseph Berliner’s improvements in connection with vulcanizers and other apparatus. Researchers will find copies of patents held by other inventors, such as Fay Oscar Farwell, Sumner Tainter, Gavin Chapman, Byron Goldsmith, Charles Francis Jenkins, as well as many others.
  - 1879-1900 (Box-folder 14/5)
  - 1900-1909 (Box-folder 14/6)
  - Gramophone, 1887-1898 (Box-folder 14/7)
  - Other patent holders, A-F (Box-folder 14/8)
  - Other patent holders, G-Z (Box-folder 14/9)
- Series 12. Photographs, 1871-1965, undated, 2 linear feet
  This series includes copies of formal portraits, Berliner working in his laboratory, family scenes with Cora Berliner and other family members, the staff of U.S. Gramophone Co., and others. There are also photographs of gramophones; Berliner’s factory in Hanover, Germany; microphones; acoustic tiles; the Technical Institute (Technische Hochschule in Hanover); the auditorium in the Oyster School, Washington, D.C.; the Berliner House at 1458 Columbia Road; and many others. Included is a photograph album, circa 1918-1923, of 56 photographs. Photographs are black and white; sizes are 10 x 13 inches and smaller.
  - 1872-1926 (Box-folder 15/1)
  - 1872-1926 (Box-folder 15/2)
  - 1881-1926 (Box-folder 15/3)
  - undated (Box-folder 15/4)
  - 1875, 1895, undated (Box-folder 15/5)
  - 1875-1907, undated (Box-folder 15/6)
  - 1927, undated (Box-folder 15/7)
  - Photograph album, circa 1918-1923 (Box-folder 16/1)
  - 1912-1932, undated (Box-folder 16/2)
  - 1912, 1915, 1924, undated (Box-folder 16/3)
  - 1910-1927, undated (Box-folder 16/4)
  - 1900-1950, undated (Box-folder 16/5)
  - 1920, 1932, undated (Box-folder 16/6)
  - 1915–1924, undated (Box-folder 16/7)
  - 1910-1965, undated (Box-folder 16/8)
  - 1910-1932, undated (Box-folder 16/9)
  - 1876, 1894, 1920, undated (Box-folder 17/1)
  - 1888, undated (Box-folder 17/2)
  - 1914, undated (Box-folder 17/3)
  - 1914, undated (Box-folder 17/4)
  - 1877, 1926, undated (Box-folder 17/5)
  - undated (Box-folder 17/6)
  - undated (Box-folder 17/7)
  - 1890-1900, undated (Box-folder 17/8)
  - 1898, 1924-1929, undated (Box-folder 17/9)
  - 1927, undated (Box-folder 17/10)
  - 1920, 1926, undated (Box-folder 17/11)
  - Emile Berliner on porch (Box-folder OS 2/1)
  - Milton King on horseback (Box-folder OS 2/1)
  - Portrait of Louise Berliner (Box-folder OS 2/1)
  - Portraits of Robert Berliner Frank (Box-folder OS 2/2)
  - Portrait of Cora Berliner (Box-folder OS 2/2)
  - Matrix plant of the Berliner Gramophone Co. (Box-folder OS 2/3)
- Series 13. Recordings, circa 1890-1950s, Over 400 sound discs, including zinc, copper, celluloid, rubber, shellac, and vinyl pressings and masters, in various speeds, and in sizes ranging from 5 to 12 inches in diameter
  Scope and Content of Series 13
  The recorded sound component of the Berliner Collection consists of over four hundred discs. These include records produced by the Berliner Gramophone Company from the mid-1890s to 1900, unpublished and experimental records, some metal discs that may be stampers or mothers, a number of recordings made for private use, a selection of electronically recorded Victor 78 rpm records, and a number of other commercially released 78s and LPs. The published Berliner records represent one of the first successful attempts to mass-market and commercially distribute popular sound recordings.
  The online Library of Congress presentation of Emile Berliner materials, entitled "Emile Berliner and the Birth of the Recording Industry," features approximately 100 sound recordings that have been converted to Broadcast WAVE and Real Audio streaming digital files. Most of the digitized discs date from the 1870s to the early 1930s, although there are a few items from as late as 1956. Each of those discs is briefly described in this series and links are provided to the online digital files for listening.
  More detailed information about the Berliner Collection sound discs, along with other Berliner recordings acquired separately from the collection, can be found in the Library of Congress Online Catalog.
  - Adeste fideles Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., 1 sound disc: analog, 63.8 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0559 (Disc Berliner 0559)
    Unidentified chimes performer.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Sept. 29, 1899.
  - Adios a Mexico Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, 69 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1216 (Disc Berliner 1216)
    Arthur B. Adamini, tenor; with piano acc.
    Autograph of Adamini inscribed in zinc master.
  - Admiral Dewey march Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Santelmann, William H. (William Henry), 1863-1932.; 1 sound disc: analog, 66.4 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0504 (Disc Berliner 0504)
    Performed by the United States Marine Band; William H. Santelmann, conductor.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Sept. 20, 1899.
    Autograph of Santelmann (conductor) inscribed in zinc master.
  - Africana. Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864.; 1 sound disc: analog, 70.3 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1113 (Disc Berliner 1113)
    Alberto del Campo, baritone; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., June 6, 1898.
  - America Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., 1 sound disc: analog, 69 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 051 (Disc Berliner 051)
    George J. Gaskin, tenor; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Apr. 5, 1899.
    Autograph of Gaskin inscribed in zinc master.
  - Auction sale, household goods Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., 1 sound disc: analog, 62 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 097 (Disc Berliner 097)
    Len Spencer, speaker.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Apr. 29, 1899.
    Autograph of Spencer inscribed in zinc master.
  - Ay chiquita Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Yradier, Sebastián, 1809-1865.; 1 sound disc: analog, 70 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1220 Z (Disc Berliner 1220 Z)
  - Bobolink Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone. 1898., Bischoff, J. W. (John W.), 1850-1909.; 1 sound disc: analog, 67.5 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 3662 Z (Disc Berliner 3662 Z)
    Virginia Powell Goodwin, soprano; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Mar. 1898.
  - Can you then love another Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Rieger, William H.; 1 sound disc: analog, 78.6 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 4159 (Disc Berliner 4159)
    S. Mantia, euphonium; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., July 25, 1898.
    Autograph of Mantia inscribed in zinc master.
  - Caramba Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1243 Z (Disc Berliner 1243 Z)
  - The carnival of Venice Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Benedict, Julius, 1804-1885.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 3257 (Disc Berliner 3257)
    Charles P. Lowe, xylophone.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., date unknown.
  - Carnival of Venice Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Benedict, Julius, 1804-1885.; 1 sound disc: analog, 70.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 3900 Y (Disc Berliner 3900 Y)
    Jean Moeremans, saxophone; piano acc.
    Autograph of Moeremans inscribed in zinc master.
  - Casey as doctor Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Hunting, Russell.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 629 Y (Disc Berliner 629 Y)
    Russell Hunting, speaker.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Mar. 20, 1897.
  - Casey's address to the G.A.R. Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 608 Z (Disc Berliner 608 Z)
    John Terrell, speaker.
  - Casey's address to the G.A.R. Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 608 (Disc Berliner 608)
    Recorded at an unknown location, June 1898.
    Autograph of Terrell inscribed in zinc master.
  - La cinquantaine Published: [United States]: Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, 74 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; Berliner's Gramophone 4808 Z (Disc Berliner 4808 Z)
    Dorothy Hoyle, violin; piano acc.
    Autograph of Dorothy Hoyle inscribed in zinc master.
  - Col. Lawley's salvation choruses Published: Washington, D.C.: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, 64.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 2002 (Disc NCPB 1100)
    John Lawley, tenor; piano acc.
    Recorded in Washington, D.C., Feb. 12, 1898.
    Autograph of Lawley inscribed in zinc master.
  - Columbia, gem of the ocean Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Shaw, David T.; 1 sound disc: analog, 69 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0792 (Disc Berliner 0792)
    Florence Hayward, soprano; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Dec. 8, 1899.
    Autograph of Hayward inscribed in zinc master.
  - Columbian anthem Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Berliner, Emile, 1851-1929.; 1 sound disc: analog, 70.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 4288 (Disc Berliner 4288)
    Performed by the Haydn Quartet.
    Autograph of S.H. Dudley (baritone and manager) inscribed in zinc master.
  - The Crack regiment Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Tobani, Theo. M. (Theodore Moses), 1855-1933.; 1 sound disc: analog, 65.2 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 79 Z (Disc Berliner 79 Z)
    Performed by Sousa's Band.
  - Dem skona Adlaida Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, 63 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 2976 (Disc NCPB 1102)
    William Mattson, baritone; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., May 28, 1898.
    Autograph of Mattsson inscribed in zinc master.
  - Eli Green's cake walk Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Koninsky, Sadie.; 1 sound disc: analog, 71 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 485 (Disc NCPB 1063)
    Cullen and Collins, banjo duo.
    Recorded at an unknown location, May 1898.
    Autographs of Cullen and Collins inscribed on zinc master.
  - Fantaisie variée Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Bruniau, A.; 1 sound disc: analog, 66 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0596 (Disc Berliner 0596)
    Jacques L. van Poucke, clarinet; piano acc.
    recorded at an unknown location, Oct. 12, 1899.
    Autograph of Jacques van Poucke inscribed in zinc master.
  - A few words in regard to drinking Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 648 Y (Disc Berliner 648 Y)
  - Fille de Madame Angot. Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Lecocq, Charles, 1832-1918.; 1 sound disc: analog, 65 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1305 (Disc Berliner 1305)
    Laure Libra, soprano; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., June 11, 1898.
    Autograph of Libra inscribed in zinc master.
  - Funicoli funicola [sic] Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Denza, Luigi.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 119 (Disc NCPB 1052)
    Performed by Banda Rossa.
    Recorded in New York N.Y., date unknown.
  - The garden of flowers Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., 1 sound disc: analog, 66.4 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0260 (Disc Berliner 0260)
    Recorded at an unknown location, June 12, 1899.
  - Che gioja Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, 68.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 3665 (Disc Berliner 3665)
    Virgina Powell Goodwin, soprano; piano acc.
    Autograph of Goodwin inscribed in zinc master.
  - Hearts and flowers Published: [United States]: Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Tobani, Theo. M. (Theodore Moses), 1855-1933.; 1 sound disc: analog, 67 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; Berliner's Gramophone 4804 Z (Disc Berliner 4804 Z)
    C. de Arth, violin; piano acc.
  - Hej mazury: Polish song no. 8. Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1900., 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 01049 (Disc Berliner 01049)
    Mr. Torowicz, tenor; with piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknwon location, Mar. 3, 1900.
  - Hello, ma baby Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Howard, Joseph E. (Joseph Edgar), 1878-1961.; 1 sound disc: analog, 64.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 05 (Disc Berliner 05)
    Len G. Spencer, baritone; piano accompaniment.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Apr. 15, 1899.
  - Her golden hair was hanging down her back Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1896., McGlennon, Felix, 1856-1943.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 563 (Disc Berliner 563)
    Maud Foster, contralto; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., Jan. 30, 1896.
  - Hold the fort: gospel hymn. Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Bliss, P. P. (Philip Paul), 1838-1876.; 1 sound disc: analog, 67.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0306 (Disc Berliner 0306)
    Len Spencer, baritone; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, June 30, 1899.
  - Home, sweet home Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Bishop, Henry R. (Henry Rowley), 1786-1855.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 337 X (Disc Berliner 337 X)
    August P. Stengler, clarinet; piano accompaniment.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Nov. 2, 1898.
  - Home, sweet home Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Bishop, Henry R. (Henry Rowley), 1786-1855.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0173 (Disc Berliner 0173)
    Unidentified chimes.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Sept. 15, 1899.
  - Hooneymoon [sic] march Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Rosey, Geo. (George); 1 sound disc: analog, 62.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 257 (Disc Berliner 257)
    Performed by an unidentified pianist.
  - A hot time in the old town Published: Washington, D.C.: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Metz, Theodore A., 1848-1936.; 1 sound disc: analog, 70.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 527 Z (Disc Berliner 527 Z)
    Dan W. Quinn, tenor; piano acc.
    Recorded in Washington, D.C., May 17, 1897.
  - Les Huguenots Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0495 (Disc Berliner 0495)
    Bernard Bégué, baritone; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Sept. 16, 1899.
    Autograph of Bégué inscribed in zinc master.
  - I don't want to play in your yard Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1895., Petrie, H. W. (Henry W.), 1857-1925.; 1 sound disc: analog, 66.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in. (Disc Berliner 178)
    Recorded at an unknown location, Oct. 29, 1895.
  - I love her just the same Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., 1 sound disc: analog, 66.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0341 (Disc Berliner 0341)
    S.H. Dudley, baritone; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, July 15, 1899.
    Autograph of Dudley inscribed in zinc master.
  - Ingersoll at the tomb of Napoleon Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone. 1898., Ingersoll, Robert Green, 1833-1899.; 1 sound disc: analog, 72.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 6013 (Disc Berliner 6013)
    W.F. Hooley, speaker.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Sept. 21, 1898.
    Autograph of Hooley inscribed in zinc master.
  - Jigs and reels Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, 65.1 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 3446 (Disc Berliner 3446)
    Marie McNeil, cornet; piano acc.
    Autograph of McNeil inscribed in zinc master.
  - Just as the sun went down Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Udall, Lyn.; 1 sound disc: analog, 69 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0323 (Disc Berliner 0323)
    Edna Florence, soprano; piano acc.